Register to the Papers of Kurt Weill and Lotte Lenya
Yale University Music Library
- Music by Weill, 1913-1983; Series I; 23.3' (41 boxes)
  - Operas, Operettas, Musicals, and Ballets, I.A
    - [Happy end. Höllenlili. Text] Ballade von der Höllenlili., [1] sheet; 30 cm. (Box 8, Folder 123)
    - [Happy end. Höllenlili. Text] Ballade von der Höllenlili: (Happy end)., [1] sheet; 30 cm. (Box 8, Folder 123)
    - [Happy end. Höllenlili. Text. English] Hoellen Lili., [1] sheet; 28 cm. (Box 8, Folder 123)
      Typescript with pencil additions and jottings on back.
    - [Happy end. Höllenlili. Text. English] Song of the Lily O'Hell / music by Kurt Weill; trans. by George Tabori., [2] sheets; 28 cm. (Box 8, Folder 123)
    - [Happy end. Hosiannah Rockefeller], 1 score (7 p.); 42 cm. R. 4, Fr. 109-115. (Box 103, Folder 124)
    - [Happy end. Hosiannah Rockefeller. Vocal score] Hosiannah Rockefeller / Kurt Weill; Brecht., 1 vocal score ([3] p.); 34 cm. R. 4, Fr. 116-117. (Box 8, Folder 125)
    - [Happy end. Kleine Leutnant des lieben Gottes] Kleine Leutnant des lieben Gottes / Kurt Weill., 1 score (14 p.); 34 cm. R. 4, Fr. 118-125. (Box 8, Folder 126)
      Two positive copies, one reverse image, laid in (35 cm. ).
    - [Happy end. Kleine Leutnant des lieben Gottes. Text] Der kleine Leutnant des lieben Gottes., [1] sheet; 28 cm. (Box 8, Folder 127)
    - [Happy end. Libretto. English] Happy end: a melodrama with songs / lyrics by Bertolt Brecht; music by Kurt Weill; original German play by "Dorothy Lane"; American adaptation and lyrics by Michael Feingold, c1972.; 69 sheets; 28 cm. (Box 8, Folder 128)
    - [Happy end. Lied vom Branntweinhändler] Vorbildliche Bekehrung eines Branntweinhändlers / Kurt Weill; Brecht., 1 score ([7] p.); 42 cm. R. 4, Fr. 126-132. (Box 103, Folder 129)
      Copy of p. [1] laid in.
    - [Happy end. Lied von der harten Nuss (Sketches)] Das Lied von der harten Nuss., pp. 7-9 of music; 34 cm. R. 4, Fr. 133-135. (Box 8, Folder 130)
      Copies of pp. 7-8 (reverse negative) are laid in.
    - [Happy end. Lied von der harten Nuss. Text] 3 Akt Song., [1] sheet; 30 cm. R. 4, Fr. 136. (Box 8, Folder 131)
      "This is the text of the Stark Nuss-Song; at least the version we just found among manuscripts: Whether it is the final version, I can't tell yet" - note on bottom of p. to "D. L." from ?.
    - [Happy end. Lied von der harten Nuss. Text] 3 Akt Song., [1] sheet; 28 cm. (Box 8, Folder 131)
    - Happy end. Mandelay-Song
      See: Happy end. Song von Mandelay.
    - Happy end. Matrosen-Song
      See: Happy end. Was die Herren Matrosen sagen.
    - [Happy end. Selections] Heilsarmeelieder / Weill; Brecht., 1 score ([3] sheets); 35 cm. R. 4, Fr. 137-138. (Box 8, Folder 132)
      Contents: Act I: 1. Geht hinein in die Schlacht [Nr. 3]. - Act II: 2. Bruder, gib dir einen Stoss (Nr. 51. Fürchte dich nicht [Nr. 6]. 4. In der Jugend gold'nem Schimmer [Nr. 7].
      Photographic negative laid in.
    - [Happy end. Selections. Vocal score] Drei Heilsarmeelieder / Kurt Weill; Brecht., 1 vocal score ([2] p.); 34 cm. R. 4, Fr. 139-140. (Box 8, Folder 132)
      Contents: I. [In der Jugend gold'nem Schimmer]. II. [Fürchte dich nicht]. III. [Bruder, gib dir einen Stoss].
    - Happy end. Song of the Lily 0'Hell
    - [Happy end. Song von Mandelay. Vocal score] Mandelay-Song: Fassung für "Happy end" / Kurt Weill; Brecht., 1 vocal score (pp. 10-11); 34 cm. R. 4, Fr. 141-142. (Box 8, Folder 133)
      Photocopy (reverse negative) laid in.
    - [Happy end. Surabaya-Johnny] Surabaya-Johnny / Kurt Weill; Brecht., 1 score (8 p.); 42 cm. R. 4, Fr. 143-150. (Box 103, Folder 134)
    - [Happy end. Surabaya-Johnny; arr.] Surabaya-Johnny / Kurt Weill, [1942-1943?] [David Drew].; 1 score ([3] p.); 32 cm. R. 4, Fr. 153-154. (Box 8, Folder 135)
      Holograph signed, in ink with pencil markings.
      An arrangement which David Drew notes was "commissioned by Bost Records Inc. for Lenya."
      No. 3 of Six Songs by Kurt Weill [David Drew].
    - [Happy end. Surabaya-Johnny; arr. (Sketches)] Surabaya-Johnny., [2] p. of music; 33 cm. R. 4, Fr. 151-152. (Box 8, Folder 135)
      Holograph in pencil with an ink correction.
      Text is not included.
    - [Happy end. Surabaya-Johnny. Text] Surabaya-Johnny., [3] sheets; 28 cm. R. 4, Fr. 155-157. (Box 8, Folder 136)
    - [Happy end. Surabaya-Johnny. Text. English] Surabaya-Johnny / Weill-Brecht; translation, Marc Blitzstein., [1] sheet; 28 cm. (Box 8, Folder 136)
    - [Happy end. Surabaya-Johnny. Text. English] Surabaya Johnny., [1] sheet; 28 cm. (Box 8, Folder 136)
      Three copies.
    - [Happy end. Surabaya-Johnny. Text. English] Surabaya Johnny., [2] sheets; 28 cm. (Box 8, Folder 136)
    - [Happy end. Surabaya-Johnny. Text. French] Sourabaya Johnny., [1] sheet; 28 cm. R. 4, Fr. 158. (Box 8, Folder 136)
    - [Happy end. Surabaya-Johnny. Vocal score] Surabaya-Johnny / Kurt Weill., 1 vocal score ([3] p.) 32 cm. (Box 8, Folder 137)
      Holograph signed in ink with pencil markings.
    - [Happy end. Surabaya-Johnny. Vocal score] Surabaya-Johnny / Kurt Weill., 1 vocal score ([2] sheets); 42 cm. (Box 103, Folder 138)
    - [Happy end. Surabaya-Johnny. Vocal score] Surabaya-Johnny / Kurt Weill. - [Wien: Universal Edition], c1929., 1 vocal score (3 [i.e. 2] sheets); 31 cm. (Box 8, Folder 137)
      Photocopy of published score.
      Pl. no.: Universal Edition Nr. 9862.
    - [Happy end. Was die Herren Matrosen sagen. Text] Matrosen-Song., [1] sheet; 30 cm. R. 4, Fr. 159. (Box 8, Folder 139)
    - [Happy end. Was die Herren Matrosen sagen. Text] Matrosen-Song., [1] sheet; 27 cm. R. 4. Fr. 160. (Box 8, Folder 139)
    - [Happy end. Was die Herren Matrosen sagen. Text] Matrosen-Song, [2] sheets; 28 cm. R. 4, Fr. 161-162. (Box 8, Folder 139)
    - [Happy end. Wenn man an einen fremden Strand kommt. Text] Havannah-Song., [1] sheet; 30 cm. (Box 8, Folder 140)
    - [Happy end. Wenn man an einen fremden Strand kommt. Text. English & German] Havana Song., [1] sheet; 28 cm. R. 4, Fr. 163. (Box 8, Folder 140)
      Text part of a letter to Lenya signed "Dolores."
    - Havana song
    - Heilsarmeelieder
    - [Huckleberry Finn. Apple Jack] Apple Jack / music by Kurt Weill; words by Maxwell Anderson. - New York: Chappell, c1954., 1 score (5 p.); 31 cm. (Box 8, Folder 141)
      Composed 1950 Jan.-Mar [David Drew].
    - [Huckleberry Finn. Apple Jack] Apple Jack / Anderson-Weill., 1 part (3 p.); 32 cm. (Box 8, Folder 141)
      Vocal-conductor part.
      "Copyright Karolina Weill and Maxwell Anderson" - bottom of p. 1.
    - [Huckleberry Finn. Apple Jack (Sketches)] Apple Jack., [1] sheet of music; 35 cm. R. 4, Fr. 164. (Box 8, Folder 141)
    - [Huckleberry Finn. Catfish song] Catfish song / Weill-Anderson., 1 score (2 p.); 32 cm. (Box 8, Folder 142)
      "Copyright by Karolina Weill and Maxwell Anderson" - bottom of p. 1.
    - [Huckleberry Finn. Catfish song] Catfish / Weill-Anderson., 1 part (3 p.); 32 cm. (Box 8, Folder 142)
    - [Huckleberry Finn. Catfish song (Sketches)] Catfish song., [1] sheet; 35 cm. R. 4, Fr. 165. (Box 8, Folder 142)
    - [Huckleberry Finn. Catfish song. Text] Catfish song., [1] sheet; 28 cm. (Box 8, Folder 142)
    - [Huckleberry Finn. Come in, sun] Come in, mornin' / Anderson-Weill., 1 part (7 p.); 32 cm. (Box 8, Folder 143)
    - [Huckleberry Finn. Come in, sun (Sketches)] Come in, sun., [3] p. of music; 35 cm. R. 4, Fr. 166-167. (Box 8, Folder 143)
    - [Huckleberry Finn. Come in, sun (Sketches)] Come in, sun., 3 p. of music; 35 cm. R. 4, Fr. 168-169. (Box 8, Folder 143)
    - [Huckleberry Finn. Come in, sun. Text] Come in, sun., 2 sheets; 28 cm. R. 4, Fr. 170-171. (Box 8, Folder 143)
      Manuscript in ink in Anderson's hand.
    - [Huckleberry Finn. Come in, sun. Text] Come in, sun., [1] sheet; 28 cm. R. 4, Fr. 172. (Box 8, Folder 143)
    - [Huckleberry Finn. Libretto (Sketches)], [5] p.; 13-28 cm. R. 4, Fr. 173-177. (Box 8, Folder 144)
      With: "I'm a wanderer," "Lady of the window...," and raft scene.
    - [Huckleberry Finn. Our private spring. Text] Our private spring., [2] sheets; 28 cm. R. 4, Fr. 178-179. (Box 8, Folder 145)
      Manuscript in pencil in Anderson's hand.
      'M. Anderson "Huck Finn"' in ink on sheet [1].
    - [Huckleberry Finn. Our private spring. Text] Our private spring., 2 sheets; 28 cm. R. 4, Fr. 180-181. (Box 8, Folder 145)
    - [Huckleberry Finn. River chanty (Sketches)] River chanty., [3] p. of music; 35 cm. R. 4. Fr. 182-184. (Box 8, Folder 146)
      'First and only manuscript of complete song. The "first draft" was already so comprehensive that no changes or alterations were needed for the printed version' - old folder.
    - [Huckleberry Finn (Sketches)], [2] p. of music; 35 cm. R. 4, Fr. 185-186. (Box 8, Folder 147)
    - [Huckleberry Finn. This time next year (Sketches)] This time next year., [3] p. of music; 35 cm. R. 4, Fr. 187-189. (Box 8, Folder 148)
    - [Huckleberry Finn, This time next year. Text] This time next year., [1] sheet; 28 cm. R. 4, Fr. 190-192. (Box 8, Folder 148)
      Three copies, one with pencil additions.
    - [Jasager] Jasager: Schuloper in 2 Akten: Partitur / Kurt Weill; Text nach dem Japanischen von Brecht, [1930 Jan-May].; 1 score (40, 44) sheets); 42 cm. (Box 103, Folder 149)
      Two title pages, one in an unidentified hand.
    - [Jasager] Jasager: Schuloper in Zwei Akten / Kurt Weill; Text aus dem Japanischen bearbeitet von Brecht. - [Wien: Universal Edition], c1930., 5 parts (9, 11, 11, 8, 6 p.); 31 cm. R. 4, Fr. 193-218 (Box 8, Folder 150)
      Incomplete, includes violin I (3 copies), violin II (2 copies), violoncello, double bass, and harmonium parts.
      "Jasager (copy-photostat made by Richmond!) sent to Jacksonville" - note laid in.
    - [Jasager. Libretto. English] Jasager / Kurt Weill; Brecht; English adaptation by Maxwell Anderson., 7 sheets; 28 cm. R. 4, Fr. 219-225. (Box 8, Folder 151)
    - [Jasager. Vocal score] Jasager: Schuloper in 2 Akten: Klavierauszug / Kurt Weill; Text aus dem Japanischen bearbeitet von Brecht., 1 vocal score (50 sheets); 42 cm. (Box 103, Folder 152)
      "aus" and "bearbeitet" in another hand on title page.
      "Gustav Brecher gewidmet" - on title page in another hand.
    - [Jasager. Vocal score] Der Jasager: Schuloper in Zwei Akten / Musik von Kurt Weill; nach dem japanischen Stuck Taniko von Brecht; Englisch von Arthur Waley, Deutsch von Elisabeth Hauptmann. - Wien: Universal Edition, c1930., 1 vocal score (51 p.); 31 cm. R. 4, Fr. 226-253. (Box 8, Folder 153)
      "Kurt Weill - South Mountain Rd. - New City, N.Y." - in Kurt Weill's hand on title page.
    - [Johnny Johnson] Johnny Johnson / Kurt Weill, c1936.; 1 score (136 [i.e. 127] p. in various pagings); 37 cm. R. 4, Fr. 254-380. (Box 9, Folder 154)
      Holograph signed, in ink with pencil and crayon additions.
      Words by Paul Green.
      Composed 1936 Jun.-Nov. [David Drew].
      Contents: Act I: Nr. 1. Introduction. Nr. 2. Over in Europe. Nr. 3. Democracy advancing. End of 1st scene and Interlude. Nr. 5. Sing-treddle, trio-traddle. Nr. 6. Come back to me. No. 6a (Reminiscence). Interlude between 2nd and 3rd scene. Captain Valentine's song. Interlude between 3rd and 4th scene. Farewell Goodbye. Tea-Song. Cowboy-Song. -- Act II: No. 25 [Nr.] 28. Johnny's Dream. [Nr.] 29. Soldier, Soldier! [Nr.] 29A. Interlude between Trench and sniper scene. Mon ami my friend. Reminiscence. Generals scene. [Nr.] 33 Dance of the generals. [Nr.] 34 Act II Scene 6. [Nr.] 35. In times of war and tumults. [Nr.] 36. -- Act III: Dr. Mahodan's song. Asylum chorus. Johnny's song. Sergeant's chant. West-Pointer.
      "Copyright 1936 by Chappell & Co., Inc., N.Y.C." - on bottom of p. 1.
      Portion of cover containing notes by Kurt Weill laid in.
    - [Johnny Johnson] Johnny Johnson / Kurt Weill, 10 parts; 10-32 cm. (Box 9, Folder 155-202, Box 10, Box 11)
      Manuscript in ink and pencil (in part, photocopies) with some additions in Kurt Weill's hand.
      Includes large folders of miscellaneous parts for each instrument, including duplicates. Many folders were labelled "Packet - ." These folders have been maintained. Several of the folders were labelled "Property of Miss Lotte Lenya":.
      - Clarinet I/Eb clarinet/bass clarinet R. 4, Fr. 381-507. (Box 9, Folder 155-158)
      - Clarinet II/alto saxophone/baritone saxophone: includes 2 copies of "Musical running order." R. 4, Fr. 508-614. (Box 9, Folder 159-161)
      - Alto saxophone R. 4, Fr. 615-651. (Box 9, Folder 162-163)
      - Trumpet I. R. 4, Fr. 652-707. (Box 9, Folder 164-165)
      - Trumpet II. R. 4, Fr. 708-796. (Box 9, Folder 166-169)
      - Trumpet I-II: includes copy of "Musical running order." R. 4, Fr. 797-858. (Box 9, Folder 170-172)
      - Trombone: Program from the Edison Theatre including list of numbers, originally laid in, now filed with programs. R. 4, Fr. 859-916. R. 5, Fr. 1-87. (Box 9; 10, Folder 173-174; 175-178)
      - Violin (violin I, violin I-III, violin I-II): includes copy of "Musical running order." R. 5, Fr. 88-270. (Box 10, Folder 179-182)
      - Violoncello: includes copy of "Musical running order." R. 5, Fr. 271-412. (Box 10, Folder 183-187)
      - Percussion R. 5, Fr. 413-547. (Box 10, Folder 188-190)
      - Banjo/guitar: includes copy of "Musical running order." R. 5, Fr. 548-654. (Box 11, Folder 191-194)
      - Piano/organ R. 51 Fr. 655-930. (Box 11, Folder 195-199)
      - Miscellaneous parts. R. 5, Fr. 931-1198. (Box 11, Folder 200-202)
    - [Johnny Johnson. Asylum chorus (Sketches)] Asylum Senate chorus: canon in 4 parts., [2] p. of music; 32 cm. R. 5, Fr. 1199-1200. (Box 12, Folder 203)
      For male chorus [David Drew], unaccompanied.
      Voice parts only.
      Begins: "Come let us hymn a hymn to peace..."
    - [Johnny Johnson. Cowboy-song. Vocal score] Cowboy-song., 1 vocal score ([4] p.); 32 cm. R. 5, Fr. 1201-1203. (Box 12, Folder 203)
      Holograph in ink and pencil.
    - [Johnny Johnson. Epitaph. Vocal score] Epitaph / Kurt Weill; Paul Green., 1 vocal score ([3] p.); 32 cm. R. 5, Fr. 1203-1204. (Box 12, Folder 203)
      Holograph signed, in ink.
      'Replaced by: "Democracy's call"' - David Drew.
    - [Johnny Johnson. Farewell goodbye. Vocal score (Sketches)] Farewell., 1 vocal score ([2] p.); 32 cm. R. 5, Fr. 1204-1206. (Box 12, Folder 203)
      Holograph in pencil with ink additions.
      'Replaced by: "Oh Heart of Love"' - David Drew.
    - [Johnny Johnson. Johnny Johnson. Text] Johnny Johnson., [1] sheet; 28 em. (Box 12, Folder 203)
    - [Johnny Johnson. Laughing generals (Sketches)] Laughing generals., [4] p. of music; 37 cm. R. 5, Fr. 1207-1210. (Box 12, Folder 203)
      Pencil sketch on back.
    - [Johnny Johnson. Libretto. Finnish] Johnny Johnson: eli tavallisen miehen tarina = (Johnny Johnson: The Biography of a Common Man) / Kurt Weill; Paul Green; Englannin kielesta suomentanut Edko Elstela, [ca. 1975].; 135 sheets; 30 cm. (Box 12, Folder 204)
      Copy of typed letter, signed from Samuel French, Inc. (Play publishers and author's representives) to Lenya (1975 Sep. 10) laid in, original with correspondence.
    - [Johnny Johnson. Libretto. German] Johnny Johnson: die Geschichte eines ganz normalen Menschen / von Paul Green; Musik von Kurt Weill; Deutsch von Ute und Volker Canaris; übersetzung der Songtexte von Dave Kamien und Joachim Preen., 169 sheets; 30 cm. (Box 12, Folder 205)
      Typescript (copy) with corrections.
    - [Johnny Johnson. Minnie Belle's song. Vocal score] Minnie Bell's song., 1 vocal score ([2] p.); 32 cm. R. 5, Fr. 1211-1212. (Box 12, Folder 206)
      Holograph in ink with pencil markings.
      'Replaced by "Farewell, Goodbye..." - replaced by "Oh heart of love"' - David Drew.
    - [Johnny Johnson. Mon ami, my friend; arr.] Mon ami, my friend., 1 score (7 p.); 35 cm. R. 5, Fr. 1213-1216. (Box 12, Folder 206)
      Manuscript in pencil with red and blue pencil additions.
      Transposed to Bb major.
    - [Johnny Johnson. Selections], 1 score (4 p.); 32 cm. R. 5, Fr. 1217-1219. (Box 12, Folder 207)
      Manuscript in pencil with colored pencil additions.
      "Continuation #34" - above caption.
    - [Johnny Johnson. Sergeant's chant (Sketches)] Sergeant's chant., [3] p. of music; 37 cm. R. 5, Fr. 1220-1221. (Box 12, Folder 208)
      "Suppressed scene" - David Drew.
      Pagination at top of pages is G-I, on the bottom of pages is 123-125.
    - [Johnny Johnson (Sketches)], [36] p. of music; 37 cm. R. 5, Fr. 1222-1242. (Box 12, Folder 209)
      [2] p. of music; 37 cm. R. 5, Fr. 1243-1244.
      Begins: "Please don't tell a soul I've run away from home."
    - [Johnny Johnson (Sketches)], [2] p. of music; 32 cm. (Box 12, Folder 209)
      See: Lady in the dark (Sketches).
    - [Johnny Johnson. Song of the goddess. Vocal score] Song of the goddess., 1 vocal score ([2] p.); 32 cm. R. 5, Fr. 1245-1246. (Box 12, Folder 210)
    - [Johnny Johnson. Tea song. Vocal score] Tea song., 1 vocal score ([3] p.); 32 cm. R. 5, Fr. 1247-1249. (Box 12, Folder 210)
      Holograph in ink with pencil markings, and additions in another hand in red pencil.
    - [Johnny Johnson. We need a man. Vocal score] Trio: "We need a man.", 1 vocal score ([4] p.); 32 cm. R. 5, Fro 1250-1252. (Box 12, Folder 210)
      'Replaced by: "Captain Valentine's Song, 'What are you coming for?'"' - David Drew.
    - [Johnny Johnson. West-Pointer. Vocal score] West-Pointer's song., 1 vocal score ([4] p.); 32 cm. R. 5, Fr. 1252-1254. (Box 12, Folder 210)
      Holograph in ink with additions in pencil and red pencil, pencil sketch at end.
      Judgment of Paris.
      See: Dreigroschenoper; arr.
    - Kanonensong
      See: Dreigroschenoper. Kanonensong; arr.
    - Kingdom for a cow, See also: I. Unidentified sketches.
    - [Kingdom for a cow], [1935 Jan.-May] [David Drew].; 1 score ([302] p.); 37 cm. R. 6, Fr. 1-161. (Box 12, Folder 211-212)
      Holograph in ink with red ink and pencil additions and words in red ink.
      English libretto by Reginald Arkell and Desmond Carter, adapted from per Kuhhandel by Robert Vambery.
      Contents: Prologue (13 p.). No. 1 (26 p.). No. 2 (5 p.). No. 3 (10 p.). President-Speech ([2] p.). No. 5. Der Mädchenraub (27 p.). No. 6 (VII p.). No. 9. Porter-chorus (11 p.). No. 10 [No. 8 is crossed out] (8 p.). No. 8 (No. 10 is crossed out] (10 p.). Swamp song ([4] p.). II. Finale 14. Second act finale ([58] p.) [in part, includes some of the original German text with English text added above]. No. 13 (11 p.). No. 17 [No. 15 is crossed out] Die Ballade von Räuber Esteban (6 p.). No. 15 [Nos. 16 and 18 are crossed out] Drinking song (8 p.). Drinking song (continued) (10 p.). No. 16. Couplet Jones (4 p.). No. 19 ([5] p.). No. 18a ([2] p.). No. 20 [No. 19 is crossed out] II. Finale (78 p.).
      Incomplete.
      Contains two different paginations.
      "Heugel & Cie." - stamp appearing several places in the score.
      "Missing (not received from Heugel, therefore probably lost by them) 1. Das Erlebnis im Café (General) No. 9, (Kurt Weill). 2. Lied der Gerichtsvollziehers (Bailiff) No. 11 (Kurt Weill). 3. Quartetto No. 12 (Kurt Weill)" - note by David Drew on old folder.
    - [Kingdom for a cow], 1 score (26, 17 sheets); 38 cm. (Box 12, Folder 213)
      Incomplete copy of full score.
    - [Kingdom for a cow. German (Sketches)], [41] p. of music; 35 cm. R. 6, Fr. 162-184. (Box 12, Folder 214)
      With sketches for "Es regnet," "Je ne t'aime pas," and Marie Galante.
      See also: B. Film Scores. You and me (Sketches).
    - [Kingdom for a cow. Libretto] Kingdom for a cow: operetta in three acts / music by Kurt Weill; adapted from the Book of Robert Vambery by Reginald Arkell; lyrics by Desmond Carter, 1935 Jul. 24.; 36, 37, 31 p.; 28 cm. (Box 13, Folder 215)
    - [Kingdom for a cow. Libretto. German] Kuhhandel: oder Der Verlobung auf Santa Maria / Musik: Kurt Weill; von Robert Vambery. (Box 13, Folder 216)
      Typescript (photocopy) with pencil additions.
      "Als Manuskript gedruckt / Alle Rechte vorbehalten / Robert Vambery / 125 No. Clark Street.
    - [Kingdom for a cow. Vocal score], [1935 Jan.-May] [David Drew].; 1 vocal score ([18] p.); 31-36 cm. R. 6, Fr. 299-314. (Box 13, Folder 217)
      Contents: Prologue (8 p., includes original, positive, and reverse image negative copy) [sheet with note laid in]. Two hearts ([5] p.). Porter-chorus [San Salvatore] ([2] p.). Couplet Jones [A Jones is a Jones] ([3] p.).
    - [Kingdom for a cow. Vocal score. German], 1 vocal score [144] p. in various pagings); 31-36 cm. R. 6, Fr. 315-418. (Box 13, Folder 218)
      Holograph, in part signed, in ink with pencil markings.
      Contents: Act I: Nr. 1. Duett (7 p.). No. 2. Terzettino (4 p.). No. 3. Auftrittslied des Generals (3 p.). [Nr. 4 [David Drew] Auftrittslied des Generals (alternate version)]. No. 3. Lied des Generals ([3] p.). No. 5. Der Mädchenraub (16 p. with pencil sketch at end). No. 7. Die Ballade vom Pharao (7 p.). No. 8. Arietta (4 p.). No. 9. Das Erlebnis im Café (4 p.). Lied des Gerichtsvollziehers (4 p.). No. 12. Quartetto (4 p.). No. 13. Juanita's Lied ([4] p.). No. 13 ([3] p.). No. 14. I. Finale (29 p.). - Act II [?]: No. 16."Fandango" (General mit das Mädchen) Drinking (4 p.). No. 17. Juan's Lied (3 p.). [No. 17]. A year ago I had a cow... ([4] p., English text). No. 20. II. Finale (40 p.).
    - Kleiner Heilsarmeelied
      See: Happy end. Geht hinein in die Schlacht. Vocal score.
    - Kleines Mahagonny
      See: Mahagonny.
    - [Knickerbocker holiday] Knickerbocker holiday / music: Kurt Weill; book and lyrics: Maxwell Anderson, [1938].; 1 score ([368] p.); 34 cm. R. 6, Fr. 419-626. (Box 13, Folder 219-221)
      Holograph signed, in ink and pencil with additions in colored pencil.
      Orchestra score, voice parts not included.
      Contents [Numbers assigned by David Drew are in brackets after the numbers which appear on the music]: Act I: Nr. 1. Introduction (22 p.). No. 2. Clickety-clack (pp. 23-37). No. 3. Entrance of the council ([3] p.). No. 3 [4x] It's a law ([8] p.). No. 4. Hush-Hush ([8] p.). No. 4. Reprise of Hush Hush ([1] p.). No. 4 [5x] I do business in my hat ([7] p.). No. 5. There's nowhere to go but up (19 p.). No. 6. It never was you (16 p.). No. 7. How can you tell an American? (20 p.). No. 7 [8x] Another law ([4] p.). No. 8 [9] Will you remember me? (13 p.). No. 9b [9a] Incidental music ([4] p.)., [10] Stuyvesant's entrance ([3] p.). No. 10 [11] One touch of Alchemy (11 p.). No. 11 [12] Exit of council ([1] p.). No. 12. [13] The one indispensable man ([7] p.) Incidental music after "The one indispensable man" ([4] p.). No. 12A [14] Young people think about love (23 p.). No. 14 [15] September song ([12] p.). 16a [16x] Clump clump swish ([4] p.). No. 15 [16] Dutch dance ([6] p.). No. 16 [17] Hail the political honeymoon (Finale I) ([11] p.). - Act II [?]: 16 [18x] Old Pete ([5] p.). No. 17 [18] Ballad of the robbers (12 p.). No. 18 [19] Sitting in jail ([6] p.). No. 19 [20] We are cut in twain (15 p.). No. 21 [22] The army of New Amsterdam ([4] p.). No. 22 [23] To war (11 p.). No. 23 [24] Our ancient liberties ([7] p.). No. 24 [25] Exit of Council ([1] p.). No. 25 [26] May and January ([8] p.). No. 26 [27y] The scars ([12] p.). [27] The scars (2nd version) ([12] p.). No. 27 [28] Algonquins from Harlem ([16] p.). No. 28 [29] Dirge for a soldier ([7] p.). No. 29 [30] No we wouldn't gonto do it [We want to make the laws] ([7] p.). No. 6 [33x] The Bachelor Song (10 p.). How far will you go with me? ([8] p.). [32y How far will you go with me - pencil sketch]. [30a Incidental music] Finale II ([2) p.).
      "The viola part is written out, or where possible, simply indicated, in the hand of Weill's assistant, Irving Schlein" - David Drew.
    - [Knickerbocker holiday. Algonquins from Harlem (Sketches)] Algonquins from Harlem., [6] p. of music; 32 cm. R. 6, Fr. 627-630. (Box 13, Folder 222)